opticks.io 2018-08-30

# Privacy Policy

Updated: May 25, 2018
                                Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy explains how Opticks and its affiliates ("Opticks",​ "we", "us", or
"our") collects, uses, discloses and transfers the personal information you provide to
us or we collect via http://opticks.io or other designated websites or IP addresses or
mobile applications, as communicated to You by Opticks Platform. It also describes
the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update
and correct your personal information.
This privacy policy explains how we make use of data and information received from
our Clients that integrate our software with their services (“Clients”) and the end-users
of those Clients (“End Users”). If not specifically defined herein, capitalized terms have
the meaning given to them in the Opticks Agreement, which is available at
https://opticks.io/legal/terms_and_conditions.pdf.
We process information under the direction of our Clients, and have no direct
relationship with the individuals whose data we process. We respect the right to
privacy of Clients and End Users. Your ability to make informed choices about the use
of your information is important to us. This privacy policy explains our policy regarding
the collection, use, disclosure and protection of any information we receive.
Information We Collect
In order to receive the Opticks's services, Clients will be required to register and
provide us with certain information, entered on our Website or given to us in any other
way, including information that can be used to personally identify Clients; such as
contact​ email,​​​contact​ phone, contact​ messenger, first​ and last name, company name,
company’s website. Clients may also provide their billing details, such as credit card
number, should they choose to activate their account right away. It is your voluntary

decision whether to provide us with any such personal information, but if you refuse to
provide such information we may not be able to register you to receive our Services.
Personal Information we collect when we obtain online feedback from you: We collect
your name, online contact information and any other personal information that you
choose to provide in the context of obtaining online feedback from you. At your option,
we may also collect your organization's name and physical contact information
although we may already hold this information if you have provided it to us for another
purpose.
Personal Information that you provide about another person: We rely on our Clients,
vendors and business partners to bring this Privacy Policy to the attention of any
individuals who they identify to us. If you provide us with information about another
person, you confirm that you have informed them of our identity and the purposes (as
set out in this Privacy Policy) for which their personal information will be processed
and that you have obtained their consent to such processing. Opticks reserves the
right to ask the other person to confirm their consent.
Analytics End Users Information We Process (Permitted Controller Personal
Data Types and Parameters)
Clients that use our Services to track the use of their services will provide us with
information regarding the characteristics and activities of their End Users. Opticks
obtains this information as a result of data being sent to our servers from the Client's
side, or when the End User is directed to our servers by the Client. The data collected
includes information such as IP address, HTTP headers, user agent, browser
properties, platform, device properties, manufacturer, OS version, and network status
(WiFi/3G), and URL information. End User data processed by the Opticks platform is
presented to our Clients to discover and prevent fraud. We provide our Clients with
aggregated and anonymous benchmark data.
Personal Information we obtain from other sources: We also may periodically obtain
both personal and non-personal information about you from Opticks subsidiaries,
business partners or resellers and other third-party sources and add it to the
information we already hold about you, such as:
        ●    Updated business address information;

        ●   Credit information about Clients, Vendors or Business Partners from credit
           reference agencies (for more information see Section “How We Use
           Information​”​below).
How We Use Information
The use of information processed by our service will be used for creating aggregate
data and anonymous data, and for internal use or for improving the services and
creating new features; data may include data of your End Users and such data of all
other Clients. We will not share Personal Information provided to us other than as set
forth under this Policy and except when required by law, regulation, subpoena or court
order. We may use Personal Information internally – for example, to help diagnose
problems with our servers, help diagnose and prevent fraudulent activity, or to improve
the Services and make Opticks more useful. We may retain Personal Information for
as long as the applicable Client account is active or as is necessary for us to provide
Services, but we may adopt shorter retention period to the extent required by our
partners. By “Personal Information” we mean any information that can be directly
associated with a specific person or entity such as a name, address, telephone
number, e-mail address, or information about activities directly linked to such person.
By analyzing the information we process (including regarding End Users) we compile
certain analytics regarding the use of our Client’s services. We provide such analytics
to our Clients. Analytics do not contain the Personal Information of any End User.
In addition, by analyzing all information we receive, we may compile aggregate or
anonymized information across a variety of services and Clients (“Aggregate
Information”). Aggregate Information is anonymous and we will not link Aggregate
Information to any Personal Information. Aggregate Information helps understand
trends and Client needs so that new products and services can be considered and so
existing products and services can be tailored to Client desires. We may share such
Aggregate Information with our partners, without restriction, on commercial terms that
we can determine in our sole discretion.
Personal Information: We use or may use your personal information for the following
purposes (or as otherwise described at the point of collection) in line with the
“legitimate interests” requirements of data protection laws:

● Creating and administering records about your online account (if you have
  one), including your organization’s purchase history;
● To provide you with information, access to resources or other products or
  services that you have requested from us on behalf of your organization;
●   To send you Client service-related communications, including in relation to
  administering your organization's online account and providing online
  services to you on behalf of your organization;
● To provide technical product support to Clients and to enhance Client
  technical product support services.
●   To deal with communications that you send to Opticks;
● To alert you to upgrades and enhancements to our products and to new
  products and/or services, including by email, in accordance with your
  communication preferences. Please see the "Client Access and Choice"
  section below for further information about how you can control these
  updates;
●   To request your feedback;
● To assess financial, credit or insurance risks arising from any relationship or
  prospective relationship with a Client, Vendor or Business Partner;
● To complete and support the current activity, Website and system
  administration, research and development, and to improve the navigation
  and content of the Website;
●   To improve the Website; and
●   To improve our products and services.

Website usage data: We use tools to measure Website visitor performance, click data,
engagements with content on the Website, pathing, form completions, etc. When
aggregated, we use it to analyze user behavior and make decisions about how to
improve the user experience. We use cookies to carry out these activities. However,
no individual will be individually identifiable in such information and statistics.
Marketing: We and our business partners may contact you by mail, telephone, fax,
email or other electronic messaging service with offers of goods, services, promotions
or other information that may be of interest to you in accordance with your
communication preferences. Where required by applicable law, your prior consent will
be obtained before sending you direct marketing and you may opt out of receiving
marketing messages from Opticks (See Section "Client Access and Choice", below).
Opticks does not in any way sell, lease or rent your information to third parties.
Anonymous and Non-personal Information: We may generate, use and disclose
aggregated anonymous and non-personal information and statistics about the Website
for marketing and strategic purposes. Similarly, we may generate aggregate usage
and statistical information related to Clients’ use of the Services in order to facilitate
analysis and comparisons.
How We Protect Information
We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information
submitted to us, we encrypt such information both during transmission and once we
receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic
storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially
acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its
absolute security. We encrypt sensitive information using secure socket layer
technology (SSL). Website users can help further protect their personal information by
using a secure web browser and by changing any access passwords regularly.
We will make reasonable commercial efforts to delete any information provided to us
by a Client upon the receipt of a written request by such Client. We cannot restore
information that we have deleted.

Legal Disclosures
We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply
with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process when we believe in
good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the
safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, or in an
emergency where the health or safety of you or another individual may be
endangered, to the extent permitted by law. Additionally, we may use IP addresses to
identify a particular user if we believe it is needed to enforce compliance with these
terms or to protect our company, employees, Website, or Clients. If Opticks is involved
in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via
email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of
your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal
information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party
with your prior consent.
Third-Party Service Providers
We may transfer your personal information (across borders and from your country or
jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world) as follows:
        ●    With Opticks affiliates, for the purposes described in Section “How We Use
            Information​”​ above;​​
        ● With our service providers or agents solely to the extent necessary to
            enable such service providers or agents to provide services to Opticks or on
            Opticks's behalf.
        ●     In response to subpoenas, court orders or other legal process, for reasons
            relating to national security, to defend against legal claims, to protect the
            rights, property or safety of Opticks, Opticks Clients, Vendors or Business
            Partners, Website users, employees or others, or as may otherwise be
            required by applicable law;
        ● To Opticks auditors, legal representatives or similar agents;
        ● To resellers for the purposes of sales and support-related matters;

       ●    To any third party that purchases, or to which a Opticks entity transfers, all
           or substantially all of the Opticks assets or business (in which case the
           relevant Opticks entity will use reasonable efforts to ensure that the third
           party to which it transfers personal information uses it in a manner that is
           consistent with this Policy);
       ● To credit reference agencies for the purposes of making periodic searches in
           the context of managing and taking decisions about Opticks's relationship or
           prospective relationship with a Opticks Client, Vendor or Business Partner.
           Such information as is provided to credit reference agencies may be used
           by other credit providers to take decisions about the Opticks Client, Vendor
           or Business Partner.
Opticks’s policy is to maintain contracts with all third parties with whom we share
personal information that restrict their access, use and disclosure of personal data in
compliance with our legal obligations.
Note that Opticks does not control the sharing of End User Personal Information;
rather, this is governed by our Client (i.e., the data controller), in accordance with the
Client’s privacy policy and applicable privacy legislation.
Client Access and Choice
If at any time you decide you do not want us to retain any personal information we
collected from you when you registered on our website, or otherwise collected about
you from others as described in Section “Information We Collect” of this Policy, you
may request we delete your information. Instructions for contacting us are provided in
Section “Access to Data​”​ of this policy. Of course, once we delete your information
you will no longer be registered with us and you will not have access to the services
that are only available through registration. As noted above, even if you are not
registered with us we collect Navigation and click-stream data, HTTP protocol
elements, and search term data, which helps us to optimize the browsing experience.
This data is not personally identifiable if you are not registered on the website.
You may opt-out of receiving marketing messages from Opticks or its business
partners without de-registering with us. To opt out of receiving marketing messages

please send an opt out email to ​sales@opticks.io​.​​​Please note that, by opting out, you
acknowledge and agree that you will not receive emails concerning upgrades and
enhancements to Opticks products. However, we will continue to send you
services-related (non-marketing) communications in connection with the administration
of your organization's account and products or services that you have requested from
Opticks on behalf of your organization.
Tracking Technologies on Our Website
When you use our Website, we automatically collect the following information:
       ●    Navigation and click-stream data
       ●    HTTP protocol elements
       ●    Search terms
This information is not identifiable to you unless you choose to register yourself on the
website.
In operating the Services, we along with our third party partners may use tracking
technologies such as cookies, E-Tags, JavaScript, beacons and Local Storage such
as HTML5.
A cookie is a small piece of text that is sent to a browser. The browser provides this
piece of text to the originating server when the visitor returns. Opticks uses cookies to
help implement its tracking technology. Opticks does not store any Personal
Information in cookies. Most Web browsers are initially configured to accept cookies,
but you can change this setting so your browser either refuses all cookies or informs
you when a cookie is being sent. Also, you are free to delete any existing cookies at
any time. Please note that some features of Opticks may not function properly when
cookies are disabled or removed.
E-Tag is a technology that is part of the standard HTTP protocol that allows our
website to validate temporary storage (cache) of our pages and images. This ensures
that you are viewing the latest version of our website since your last visit.

JavaScript is a dynamic object oriented computer programming language. JavaScript
is used to understand user behavior on our website.
Local Storage (LS) such as HTML5 and Local Shared Objects (LSOs) such as Flash
are used to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer
their own management tools for removing HTML5 LS’s.
Beacons are clear graphic image(s) of 1×1 pixel that is delivered through a web
browser usually as part of a webpage request. Web beacons operate as a tag that
records an end users visit to a particular webpage.
As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically, such as
Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP),
referring/exit pages, operating system and/or clickstream data.
Use of Opticks by Children
Opticks does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of
18, and you must be 18 years of age or older in order to establish an account for
Opticks. In the event you become aware that an individual under the age of 18 has
enrolled, please contact us immediately at sales@opticks.io and we will remove their
information from our system immediately.
Geo-Location
We may collect geo-location information from Clients and users that enable this
feature.
Third-Party Links
From time to time, the Website may contain links to other websites owned by
non-Opticks affiliated entities and we may display advertisements from third parties on
our Website. When you click on these links, you enter another website. Opticks is not
responsible for the content, operation or privacy practices of any such websites. Your
use of such websites will be subject to any terms of use posted on such websites and
not by the terms of use of the Website. In particular, unless expressly stated, we are

not agents for these sites or advertisers, nor are we authorized to make
representations on their behalf.
Commitment to protecting children’s privacy
Special Note to Parents​:​ ​Opticks does not knowingly collect personal information
from ​children under the age of 18, and you must be 18 years of age or older in order to
establish an account for Opticks. If you are a parent of guardian who knows or has
discovered that you child under the age of 18 has submitted his or her personal
information or other information without your consent, permission, or authorization;
upon request, we will promptly remove your child’s personal information or other
information from our database, cease the use of such information and direct any other
party with access to such information to do the same.
Access to Data
We have no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information we
process. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete
inaccurate data should direct his query to the service provider (the data controller). If
an End User wishes us to remove his or her Personal Information stored with us (if
any), he or she may send us an e-mail to sales@opticks.io,​and we will respond to their
request within a reasonable timeframe.
Opticks seeks to ensure that your information and preferences are accurate and
complete. You have the right to update your information and/or preferences at any
time. If you wish to review or change the information we have regarding you or to
update your preferences regarding our retention or use of your personal information
please let us know by sending an e-mail with your name, full mailing address and
e-mail address to sales@opticks.io together with a description of the changes you
request.
In certain circumstances, persons in the EU may have rights of rectification (where
data is inaccurate), erasure, restriction, objection or portability. EU persons may also
have a right to receive from us a copy of their personal data we have in our
possession. To exercise these rights or to obtain a copy of the personal information we
hold about you, please write to the above address.

Further, Jarvis Digital, a company incorporated and existing in Spain, whose principal
office is at C/Amigo 11 Barcelona 08021 Spain, is the place of central administration
for Opticks in the EU and as such is the “Main Establishment” for Opticks in the EU.
EU Data subjects seeking to make changes to the information we have regarding you
or to update your preferences regarding our retention or use of your personal
information can send an e-mail with your name, full mailing address and e-mail
address to sales@opticks.io together with a description of the changes you request.
Data Retention
We may retain Personal Information we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as
needed to provide services to our Clients. We may adopt shorter retention periods if so
directed by them. We may retain and use this Personal Information as necessary to
comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Changes
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices
from time to time. If we make any material changes we will notify our Client by email or
by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We
encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy
practices. You will be deemed to have accepted such amendments by your continued
use of the Website after the effective date.
Questions, Objections and Complaints
We are responsible for our collection, use and disclosure of EU Personal Data in
accordance with the Principles. We also are responsible for onward transfers to third
party agents that are processing such data on our behalf, unless we prove that we are
not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. In certain situations, we may
be required to disclose EU Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public
authorities, including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements.
Where we are relying on our legitimate interests to process your personal data (see
section “How We Use Information​”​ above), you have the right to object to such
processing. To exercise your right to object, please contact us as specified above. We

will consider your objection and we will comply with it unless we have a compelling
legitimate ground as permitted by applicable law.
Opticks is committed to reply to any questions and resolve any complaints you have
about our collection or use of your Personal Data. Anyone with inquiries or complaints
regarding our collection or use of his or her Personal Data may contact Opticks as
specified above.
